<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Davis Marques</title>
    <link>https://elmarquez.github.io/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Davis Marques</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://elmarquez.github.io/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IFCCA Competition for the Design of Cities</title>
      <link>https://elmarquez.github.io/posts/ifcca-competition-for-the-design-of-cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elmarquez.github.io/posts/ifcca-competition-for-the-design-of-cities/</guid>
      <description>In 1998, the International Foundation for the Canadian Centre for Architecture (IFCCA) held an ideas competition called the Competition for the Design of Cities. The challenge of the competition was to create a speculative design for a sixteen block area of Manhattan (Figure 1). The IFCCA invited a coterie of internationally recognized architects to participate. Among that group was the team of Morphosis Architects and George Yu.
Morphosis Architects is an internationally recognized architectural design firm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Inquiry into the Process of Design Exploration</title>
      <link>https://elmarquez.github.io/posts/an-inquiry-into-the-process-of-design-exploration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elmarquez.github.io/posts/an-inquiry-into-the-process-of-design-exploration/</guid>
      <description>Design is distinguished in many respects from other intellectual endeavors.
Simon explains that, &amp;ldquo;The natural sciences are concerned with how things are. &amp;hellip; Design, on the other hand, is concerned with how things ought to be, with devising artifacts to attain goals.&amp;rdquo; 1 Designers interpret design problems and formulate design objectives. They explore opportunities and represent possibilities, reflect on prior designs and communicate design proposals to others. Designs are contingent upon the contexts in which they arise.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
